Translated By The Community Of WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
After fifty-five days marooned in Samoa, tonight...
someone will be crowned Australia's "Sole Survivor".
Just three remain.
Army corporal El.
- El...wins...immunity.
- Yes.
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
Ex-cricketeer Lee.
What a Herculean effort that is.
There's the notion out there that you have to lie,
you have to cheat, you have to backstab
and I'm of the belief that
you don't have to do that to win the game.
And Kristie...who's emerged as one of the
game's biggest risk-takers.
I need to get to get to the end of this game.
No matter what.
Last time...faced with the choice
of aligned with mood-maker Flick
or the physically dominant power couple of
- Lee and El...
- I'm here for a challenge and
got to take that challenge on.
They have such a strong bond. Where do you fit?
Well, then I have to win the immunity tomorrow.
Kristie chose the power couple.
Good luck.
Eighth member of our jury...Flick.
- She sent Flick to the jury.
- You're an idiot.
We'll see.
Flick...the tribe has spoken.
And set up an epic David and Goliath showdown.
Tonight...the most brutal final challenge
in survivor history.
Who will outwit,
outplay and outlast all others
to win the half-million dollars and the
title...of "Sole Survivor"?
Walking...toward that final immunity challenge...
you could just...feel the scenery around you.
The reality really sunk in, that...
I am actually
in the top three.
It was very surreal...
to look at...a whole...row
of all the torches of every
contestant in front of you.
You were stopping to acknowledge
each and every one of them.
And think...I've outlasted...
all of those people.
Rats.
- Oh, good old Dez.
- Ah, Dez. Ha-ha.
You know, such a guy.
I'd like to be remembered as...
don't matter what age you are,
you can always
apply for some big adventure
and you might be lucky enough
to live your dreams.
- Bianca.
- Well, I work in insurance
and it's mind-numbing, which is why I'm here.
For some pizazz.
- Evan.
- Ha-ha, funny weird.
I swear on my wife's life...
that I'm not goin' ask you.
I could swear on anything.
- Ah, Peter.
- Peter!
- Tough decision to leave the game.
- Yeah.
- Real time. Back in the real time.
- I'm gonna miss you.
Love  ya, Pete.
Barry...the one that
we all wanted to meet.
- Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
- Well, good night.
Good night.
- Tegan?
- Oh, she started on yellow and then went to blue.
- Rohan. Poor fellow.
- Oh, what a beautiful name.
I work as a model.
I've got it down pat, so I just...
Find me, I'll be over here, doing these ones, yeah.
Oh, Kat.
- Lovely girl.
- Yeah, such a nice gal.
Didn't really know Andrew.
He  was a superfan. Probably too much of a
Probably...too much of a superfan for his own good.
I'm probably the smartest person here.
I'm very much in control of this tribe.
And if you step out of line...you'll be hit...
you'll be shot...you'll be swimmin' with the fishes.
Oh, Craig.
- What a character.
- Craig is going
one-handed right now. I'm impressed.
- Thanks, Jonathan.
- Ha-ha-ha-ha.
- Ahh. Phoebe.
- Phoebe.
Tried to get me out and
she ended up going home.
I came here to play. I came here to play hard.
I had an impact on the game, I was a big player
and a strategic player. And I'm just
stoked that I got to be part of it.
- Conner.
- Oh, Conner.
I came in, wanting to play aggresively.
- But when you're here...
- It's alright.
you just decide I'm gonna be me.
And you make real connections
with these people.
It's a lot harder than I actually thought it would ever be.
- Kate.
- Really great person.
- I'm just glad every day to be alive.
I was given a second chance
and...I'm gonna do the best
I can with this second chance.
Ah, Nick. Played the game very hard.
What if we...say that there was a
clue to the hidden immunity idol...
but we tell everyone the wrong clue.
Eww.
I was able to...really stir thing up.
And..that, I guess, is the real goal.
Come out here, get to play, and make an impact.
Kylie.
- Ehh.  Excellent Kylie.
- Ah, Kylie, my Kylie.
- Sue.
- Ahh.
- Seething Sue.
- Yeah.
Sue...Sue, you hold that rope,
you show everyone what you've got. Yeah?
- JL.
- She wanted to be known for her big move.
The people that don't know where they
see an alliance, they should be thinking
about making big moves.
- I-I like Brooke.
- Yeah.
Too scared to hook up with.
I would love to be remembered
for my endurance challenges
- and just for surprising people.
- Brooke wins.
Oh, and I've even surprised myself.
Ah, Sammy boy.
Blue tribe, Saanapu, wins fire!
On, Sammy!
Ah, Matt.
- I'm a magician.
- So...
- let's-let's...you're a magician?
- Make magic happen.
I mean nothing.
You think the physical element of this game is tough.
There we go. Come on.
But, mentally, it is so much tougher.
If you're gonna play this game...accept the fact
that you're gonna do things that
in your real life you wouldn't do.
- Flicky.
- Flicky, flipper.
A-class, even up to the last second.
I think a lot of people underestimated me,
both socially and strategically.
- I'm thinking of trying to get Brooke out.
- Me, too.
- If you wanna talk about that...
- A hundred percent.
I've been in a couple of big moves in this game.
and I'm really proud of myself for that.
That's what I wanted to do.
I wanted to make my own moves.
Epic.
The final immunity challenge is the most
important challenge...that you could win.
Because you are guaranteed the top two players.
Be great...El and I
made the final two.
- Wow, look at this. It's molting.
- See...that's just volcanic.
I know it's not gonna be easy,
I know I'm gonna have to fight it out.
There's a half-a-million dollars and the title of
"Sole Survivor" at stake.
I want to win it...so...much.
The odds...are not in my favor.
I am up against...
the two strongest
physical competitors out here.
Who are best friends...probably are gonna
take each other to the end.
But my dream has always been to take out the
title of "Sole Survivor"...and...
that is something...
that I'm never...
gonna give up on.
Ever.
- Wow, what a setting.
- Wow.
- Beautiful.
- Epic.
- Wow, right? Fitting finale.
- Yes, it is.
Guys...ready to get to your final...
- immunity challenge.
- Ahh.
- Absolutely.
- Yes.
- Yes?
First things first.
- El.
- Okay.
Gotta take it back.
- Sure.
- Thank you.
For the last time.
Immunity is back up for grabs.
The winner...is guaranteed a spot in the final two.
And...you get to decide...
who will be sitting next to you
at the final Tribal Council.
Guaranteed a fifty-percent chance
of winning half-a-million dollars...
- Wow.
- and the title of "Sole Survivor".
- If you only win one immunity challenge...
this is the one to win.
Also...
to give you guys a little extra motivation today...
there are some special people here
- to cheer you on.
- No...
- Oh, my God.
- Nooo.
Come on out, guys.
Ohhh, Lee.
That's my sister.
Oh, God, John.
To give you guys a little extra motivation today...
There are some special people here to cheer you on.
- No. No.
- Oh, my God.
- Come on out, guys.
- Ohh.
- Oh, God, it's John.
- Good God.
Watch it, John.
Ohh.
Oh, my God.
Ohh, I...
Oh, my...John.
Oh, my God.
Don't lose hope. So proud of you.
Don't let me go!
I...just...can't comprehend that
my dad is gonna be there...for that
final immunity that I need.
I just couldn't believe what I was seeing.
Ohh...to see you.
Family is-is everything to me...so...
your sister...
that is such a special moment.
Hell, I just...I lost it.
- I can't believe what you look like.
- I hope you like this.
- Look at that.
- I've never seen so much hair on you.
- Ohh, man.
- Oh, God.
I love you so.
Ha-ha-ha. Ha-ha.
I just can't believe this is happening.
Having my sister there was...
It was incredible,
like...yeah, it was amazing.
Just getting to touch here and hug her and...
means everything.
Maura.
How proud are you...of your sister?
I'm so proud. Yes.
Yep, I'm so proud of her.
- Thanks, babe.
- Like I knew she'd be here and, eh...
she's amazing. She's gone through some stuff
and she's just come out stronger.
She does so much for other people. Um...
and as a mom, it's...it's easy to get...
so caught up in...your child that you
forget about yourself. So, to see her...
doing something for her...
Oh, babe...you're gonna make me cry.
That's really good.
Yep. Love you.
Kristie.
- Yes.
- You seem particularly emotional...today.
What-what does this mean to you...
- seeing a loved one turn up?
- It...
This is actually...
m-my dream of an eight-year-old.
I...ha...I literally sat there...
next to my dad and watched
Richard Hatch...in this...challenge...
and turned to him and said...
"One day I'm gonna get on Survivor."
Wow.
- Wow.
- "And one day, I'll be there."
- To me, that's...
- And I'm here.
- It's amazing.
- Yeah.
- You're here.
Anthony.
- You remember that day?
- Sure do, mate.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Of course.
Every episode. From day one, Kristie said that she was
gonna get on the show. As an eight-year-old.
And every since, it's been one of the...
It's probably been one of the driving passions.
She's a very determined person as you may well
- have learnt. So...
- Very.
She can do anything.
She leaves all her emotions out there.
I-I've always encouraged her to just see who she is.
So...
I'm sure that's what she's done.
And that's what makes me most proud...is to be herself.
I told you...I gave up my love letter...
- to somebody else.
- I-I knew you would.
I knew, if she had the opportunity...
to give it to somebody else...
she'd be prepared to forego it.
Anthony, in...fifty-four days
she won one reward.
- And that one reward...
- Yes.
Yep.
- she gave up, you know.
- Yep.
Lee, you seem quite emotional
right now. What's going on with you?
Well, everything, mate, everything.
Um...
it's great to see my family, you know, and I...um...
we-we thought it might
happen at some stage, but not today.
And just see 'em...pop over the cliff there...
I can't ex-explain it. Family's everything to me.
Rachel, how proud are you...
of your brother getting this far?
Oh...I'm so proud.
I know he's got the strength, he can do it.
He had major back surgery...
being told you're never gonna...run or walk again.
And...they just said..."Your cricket's over."
"You're not playing again."
And he went on to...not only...
to play again, but...top level.
So, I know he's got it in 'im.
And...
I know he's got that inner strength, that drive...
and I know whatever he put his mind to, he can...achieve it.
So, I know he can do it.
Wow.
So proud of 'im.
Alright, I hate to break this up, but, loved ones, you
you are here to inspire these guys to win today.
So, I'm just gonna get you to take...a seat over there.
And then we're gonna get on it.
Don't give up.
- You can do this.
- Yeah, no sweat.
- I'm gonna give all I have.
- You will.
Alright, Survivors. Today's challenge is very simple.
It's all about endurance.
You will stand on pedestals with one hand on an idol.
If at any point..either foot comes off the pedestal...
or your hand comes off the idol
or your free hand touches
the idol or the post that it's on...
you're out of the challenge.
Last person left standing...wins immunity...
guaranteed a spot in the final two.
And...
you get to decide
who will be sitting next to you
at the final Tribal Council.
- Wow.
- You know the drill.
We're gonna draw for spots.
And then we're gonna get to it.
Okay.
For immunity...
and a spot in the final two.
Survivors, take your positions.
This challenge...is now on.
Wow.
This challenge looks simple.
But that position is awkward.
Let go of that idol...
you could be letting go of your place in the game.
All it will take is one lapse in concentration.
To lift up a foot.
To move your hand.
And that's it.
You're out of the challenge.
You gotta block out all of the elements.
The wind...the waves...the sun.
Me...babbling on.
You need to stay focused.
You need to remember why you started
this fifty-four days ago.
This the last...
challenge...in Australian Survivor.
The longer this goes on...
the more fatigue...
you will experience in your body and mind.
Gonna start to feel it...
in your back...
feet.
Who wants it more?
- Wave.
- Ohh.
Whoa!
- Wave.
- Ohh.
- Whoa!
- This is the last...challenge...
in Australian Survivor.
That position is awkward.
Don't take those feet off the pedestal.
Let go of that idol...
you could be letting go of your place in the game.
Guys, it's one hour.
Oh-ho.
You guys are just getting saturated by these waves.
El.
Trying to get a comfortable position.
Lee, that's not an option for you?
Naw. My knees are cooked, buddy.
If I go down on 'em
I'm not coming back up, so...
I'm-I'm gonna have to stand up on this one.
Oh, wow.
Wind's picking up.
Making it a little more difficult to balance.
What's it like up there?
It's surreal being here.
- Surreal?
- Yeah. On the last challenge.
- Yeah.
- We beat some amazing people.
And tonight...
it's gonna be fun.
- It gonna be a fight?
- Yeah, I like it.
- You like a fight?
- I like a fight, yeah.
I notice that you've been shuffling around
- on this pedestal...quite a bit.
- Yeah.
- Feet?
- Uh...
- Feet are startin' to irritate you?
Yeah. Feet and hands...everything.
Yeah.
The sun.
How you feeling, Kristie?
- Good.
- Yeah?
Yeah...good.
Anything hurting?
No hurt can...compare to the hurt of...
walkin' away.
How about you, Lee? How you feeling?
Trying to get those feet comfortable?
Yeah.
They're big feet, but...
doesn't necessarily mean a good
thing when you're on these little poles.
Waves are gettin' bigger.
You guys are gonna get wetter and wetter.
This is what Survivor is about.
Never...giving...up.
That necklace has some serious power tonight.
Not only does it make you immune...
but you get to decide who goes to the jury...
and who comes with you to the final Tribal Council.
Laura...what qualities...
do you think El possesses that have gotten her
through...the last fifty-four days?
She's a very
motivated person, like she's competitive with
herself and if there's something that she wants to do...
she'll just go in a hundred percent. She doesn't let up
if she wants to do something and do it well.
Mwah.
We could be here for a while.
We could be here for a while, yes.
Rachel...
why do you think Lee is...
doing this?
His two beautiful boys...
didn't see the heart of his cricket career.
They was very, very little when he went
- through all of his back surgeries...
- Um-hmm.
so...he wants to show them that this is what
you can do if you put your mind to something.
He wants them
- to be proud of him.
- Hmm.
And...just teach the boys, you know,
if this is your goal, this is your dream, you can do it.
So, Anthony, what are you thinking
about your daughter's determination?
- Doesn't surprise me a lot.
- No?
- Has she always been like that?
- Yeah...yeah.
Yep. Kristie's mother and I
separated when...Kristie was eight.
So, one of the things that, you know,
we really...tried to work on was...
just building up...their inner strength,
the two kids.
And, just coincidentally,
started with Survivor. It was like,
especially since the time we separated,
Survivor'd just started.
And so, we'd sit down...watch every episode.
She would tell me, "Dad..."
"I'm gonna be on the show."
For her...it certainly, um...
played a massive part...being able to cope with adversity.
Which is life.
You've now been standing in that position...
three hours.
- Wow.
- Whooo.
- Well done.
- Yeah!
Ohhhh.
Anyone feel like stepping down?
Kristie, is that fatigue starting to set in now?
No.
- Got some bad news, though.
- That was awesome.
What's that?
We're not even at high tide yet.
- Yeah we are.
- Not yet.
Five hours.
- Five hours.
- This is nice.
- No, really?
- Stay calm.
- Put on some bree.
- Whoo.hoo.
Whoo-ho-ho.
- Ohh.
- I want some bree.
Lost sensation in your feet.
Drenched...you're cold...shivering...miserable.
Oh, ho! Ohh!
Those waves are relentless.
This challenge is open-ended.
It can go all night.
Those pedestals are becoming more slippery
with every passing minute.
Tide is really coming in now.
- Wow.
- Everyone's showing
the kind of determination it takes
to become the "Sole Survivor".
Oh, no...no, no, no, no.
Ooohhh!
Ohhh! Oh.
Oh.
Guys, you've been here for six hours.
- Yes.
- Whoo.
Come on, Bree.
Amazing performance.
Come on, babe. Heat wave.
He's left.
This challenge only gets harder and harder.
Ahhww!
The three of you battling it out for that necklace.
Guaranteed safety tonight at Tribal Council.
Awwwwwkkkik!
This is really gonna test you now.
XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX
Ohh.
_
XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX
Hey.
_
El, you're looking really cold now.
Everyone's pushed to their limit.
Who's gonna be the last one standing?
Ohhwww!
Another night to play.
Awwwwkkk!
Here. Put your arm around me.
- Okay.
- It's alright.
- Walk.
- Okay.
Big boy.
Really kidding, what?
Great effort. Great.
- Ohh.
- Six hours and twenty minutes, El.
I'm gonna bring you down to your sister, okay?
- Dangerous, baby. Come here and let me...
- Well done, well done.
I'm proud of you.
Lee...you've gotta let me have this one.
You've gotta let me have this one.
I don't wanna go home.
I'll take you. I'll take you.
If you let me have this immunity,
I will take you.
Promise.
You gave me an opportunity in this game
that I could never have gotten without you.
I swear to God.
I promise. I will take you.
And you know you can probably beat me.
I don't think I'm gonna get any votes.
I just wanna get to the end.
I just wanna be sitting in the final two.
_
And you're deserving.
Keep fighting.
- Yeah. You keep fighting.
- I am.
I am fighting. I'm really fighting.
Come on, Lee.
And the other reason why I'd take you...
is because...
you remind me so much of my dad...
who's sitting, perched over there.
_
You always were supporting me.
.                                                     though.
_
Do I?
I swear on my dad.
I swear on me.
_
You are making...a young...
eight-year-old girl's dreams...
come true.
Ahhwww
It's so heavy.
Ahh!
Ahh! Ohh, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
You okay, man?
I...
- Kristie, you okay.
- Nooo.
Can you get me off Lee?
If I've hurt him...
Ohh. Ohh.
My God!
There she is.
- Stay where you are. You stay...
- Oh, my God.
I'm sure you would. You'd do the patent.
- Okay?
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God!
- You did it.
- Ohh.
- Okay.
Yes...wanna...
Ohh. Ohh.
- One big try.
- Okay.
Ohh. Oh. Did you hurt yourself?
You're all right.
I did it. You needed to.
The only one that I won.
That's the only one you needed to win.
- The only one I needed.
- That's the only one that mattered.
And you knew that.
I needed it.
Every one except this.
Every one.
Ohh.
- Hi, babe.
- Tough it out.
- Oh, babe.
- Ahh.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, no, no, no, no. No, that was...
That was...that's all...
- So heavy...
- I had fear for you.
You've known that I can...how many times.
I just wanted to convince
that was God.
I assumed it, that I was never gonna make it.
And I just kept going.
- Find a way. That's it.
- I found a way.
That's it. Just find a way.
Kristie.
Congratulations.
- Yeah.
Not only did you win.
individual immunity after fifty-four days,
you won the most important...individual
immunity challenge there is in this game.
- You said you were gonna do it...and you did it.
- You did.
- Yeah.
- Well done.
- That's right.
- Well done, Kristie.
- Well done.
Six and half hours. Incredible.
- Epic.
- Now, normally, I'd call you over.
- But I'm gonna get dad to come over.
- Alright.
Come over, dad.
- Wow.
- Yeh!
- Yoo-hoo!
- No way.
- I'm gonna get him to do the honors.
- Thanks very much.
Wow!
I want you to take that back.
I want you to put it on your daughter's neck.
- How good's that?
- Yeh!
- Congratulations.
You have made it to the final two.
- Oh, wow.
- You will get to see
day fifty-five and you will get to plead your
case to the jury...as to why you
deserve...to be the "Sole Survivor".
Oh, my God.
But before you get to that, you have a very important
decision to make. Because your vote tonight...
will decide...which of these two
goes to the jury and which of these
two goes with you...
to the final Tribal Council.
It's a big decision.
Let's get it done.
Well done, everyone. Let's get out of here...
- Yes.
- Ohhh!
- before wwe get rained on again.
I won the most important
necklace in this game...with my dad
standing there with the most iconic
challenge...in Survivor history.
That...is something I will
remember...for the rest of my life.
And now, I just have to make...
the vote for the last member of the jury.
Lee or El.
This...is a half-million dollar decision tonight.
And I don't really wanna mess it up.
Evening. How are you guys. Well.
- Well, well.
- Good evening.
We'll now bring in the members of our jury.
Nick...Kylie...
Sue...Jennah Louise...
Brooke...Sam, Matt...
and Flick.
Voted out last Tribal Council.
How!
Oh, my God.
I can't believe she won.
Wow, guys.
I don't think words...can describe
just how incredible...
that challenge was today.
Seriously, you were out there...
for almost six and a half hours,
standing on those painful little posts...
relentlessly pounded by waves...
taunted by me and
you never...ever gave up.
Kristie.
Last night,  you sat here at Tribal Council,
you said to me...
that you're gonna have to win the challenge
today if you're gonna end up
in the final two, and you did it.
Yeah.
That was a pretty great moment.
It's a dream come true.
Anything from here is just...
icing on the cake.
Well, congratulations.
- Yeah, it's amazing.
- I know...I don't know...
Alright.
I wanna talk a little bit about the vote.
So...tonight...
because Kristie has the immunity necklace,
it means you can't vote for her.
El and Lee...you can't vote for yourselves,
they can only vote for each other, which means that...
your votes, technically, cancel each other out.
- Yeah.
- Know that. Yep.
So...the only vote that will count tonight...
is Kristie's.
So...Kristie, your vote will decide...
which of these two...
will be...the last member...of the jury.
But before we get to that...
El...Lee, I'm gonna give you
both a chance...
to pitch your case...
to Kristie...
why...she should take you to the final two.
- El.
- God, ohh.
What you see is what you get with me. Um...
I don't think I have really...
beaten around the bush with you, at all.
Um, I've tried to support you
throughout this whole journey you've gone on.
I think...I'm less likely to get the votes off the jury.
Okay.
- Lee...your turn.
- What am I gonna say? Um...
I don't know. I...yeah, we've...
all three of us have been together since
day one and...it's up to her...it's her choice.
Ah, whatever she decides, I'm-I'm happy with.
I'm not gonna...scrap and fight into this...
you know, claw her eyes out or anything like that, or...
Just let her be.
Let her make her decision.
It's the first time that she can have a decision
by herself without any pressure.
Alright.
Kristie, it's time for you to vote.
But remember, you are voting
for the person that you want to put...
on the jury. Time to vote. You're up.
I'll collect the vote.
I'll read the vote.
Twenty-second person voted out
from Australian Survivor...
and the final member of our jury...
El.
You need to bring me your torch.
Oh, no.
See ya. See you tomorrow.
- Bye, send me..
- Yeah.
I'll see ya. Bye, guys. Next trip.
This is cool.
El...the tribe has spoken.
Time to go.
Been an honor, guys. See you guys tomorrow.
So long.
Well, Kristie...and Lee,
congratulations, you are the final two.
Thanks, mate.
- Thank you.
- You've done everything you can
and now it's up to them...the jury.
Grab your torches. Head back to camp.
Enjoy your last night on the beach.
And I'll see you at the final Tribal Council.
Well done.
- Thanks, Jonathan, appreciate it.
- Me, too.
Pit Stop.
Come here, buddy.
The last day...
Ha.
Yes! And my arm is still dead.
Ahhh! I made it to day fifty-five!
Ha!
No more challenges.
The only challenge is...
getting that jury on-side.
Huh!
That's the only thing I've gotta do now.
- Very last mark.
- Yeah.
Very last mark-up. You deserve to
notch that last one.
Congratulations to us...
- Yes.
- the top two
Top two, wow.
- Fifty...five days.
- Yep.
That's amazing. That is really amazing.
It was a special moment with Dez, you know.
We're both in with a shot...
of winning...the first ever Australian Survivor.
Oh, there's a little more than just
the note in there.
Aha! There's a feast.
- We've got bread.
- We've got bread. We have eggs.
- Tomatoes...
- Lo and behold...
it is a little mini-banquet...
so that we can enjoy the last day.
- There is bacon.
- There's Bacon!
We have bacon.
Bacon and egg roll!
Bacon egg roll.
Ohh.
What a treat.
Oh, yes.
We're gonna be ready to go.
Ready to take on whatever the jury throws at us.
_
.                                             - I think so.
Yeah, they'll be...
firing off questions.
People...didn't think I was gonna make it.
But...I have survived
through everything Survivor has thrown at me.
And...I'm out the other side.
Om...
Ha-ha.
Chick...en.
I have absolutely
no idea what I'm gonna say to the jury tonight.
I...hope that I played...
as truthful and honest game as I possibly can.
It's nigh impossible to do that...
on Survivor. However, I've tried to go as
close as I possibly can...
and, yes, I've had to vote off...everyone who's
on the jury. But...I am hoping that if the jury takes
in my overall game...
that...
I can be this game's survivor.
Let's have one last look at it.
- One last look.
Fia-Fia.
Take it all in.
I just got chills.
That's great...it's not over.
- It is exciting.
- End of the chapter.
It is.
I can't believe this is the end.
- You alright?
- Yeah.
- I'm alright.
- Let's go smash this Tribal Council, hey?
Let's do it!
Kristie and I are two entirely different people and players.
I base my game probably more about physicality and the
social side of things, less so strategy.
Kristie was probably more strategy...
and independence.
Two totally different...ways
in which we played the game...so...
it's hard to tell. You got nine...
jury members up there and each one of them's
got  different theories.
I've very happy
with how I've played the game.
- Good people can win.
- See you later, Fia-Fia.
Fia-Fia.
And...
- Let's go.
- let's go.
I do feel as though I deserve
to be the "Sole Survivor".
I've proved that you can defy...
all the odds.
I did that.
And...isn't that what Survivor is all about?
I'll now bring in the members of our jury.
Nick...Kylie...
Sue...Jennah Louise...
Brooke...Sam...
Matt...Flick...
and El...
voted out at the last Tribal Council.
Kristie...Lee...Congratulations.
You have done what twenty-two others who
started this game were unable to do.
You have lasted...all fifty-five days.
Well done.
- Thanks, mate.
- Thank you.
The two of you have gone as far
as you can go...in this game. And tonight,
the power now shifts...
to the jury...nine people who you had...
either directly or indirectly, a hand in voting out,
are now gonna decide which of you
deserves to win.
Now, up until this point, the jury has remained silent.
But tonight, they will have a chance
to address you. Now, they can ask you anything.
But remember...whatever you
say to the jury could make or break your game.
Okay. So this is how it's gonna work.
Each of you is gonna make an opening statement.
This is your chance to make your case to the jury.
Why you deserve the title of "Sole Survivor"...
and the half-million dollars that goes with it.
Then, one by one, they will address you.
Then, they will go to vote...to decide...
who wins Australian Survivor
Okay, let's get the opening statements.
Lee...what would you like to say to the jury?
Um...
A couple of things. I-I-I came into this...
wanting to play a game full of trust...
loyalty and respect. And I know they're buzzwords...
but...I was really keen
to live...my normal life...outside...
and bring it into the Survivor world.
And I believe that I could of...
I could do it and I could achieve it. Not only that,
that I wanted to do it for my boys as well,
in the sense that you can play...a clean and honest game
at Survivor...and
I wanted to...make them proud as well.
That, in all, has somehow...
played a huge part in me being here...tonight.
Obviously, I've played a part in, you know...
voting each one of you guys off.
But...I believe, at the time...
I was stuck, loyal and trustworthy,
and never budged...
from what I believed was the alliance at the time.
Yeah, that's all I really have to say. Um...
about that.
Kristie...what would you like to say to the jury?
All of you...
You thought I was...absolutely crazy.
Maybe I was.
But, I've proven
that every single odd can be stacked against
you in this game...but if you keep going
and you're determined enough, you will find
a way to make it to the end.
I've had to do...
lots of different things...
to be able to get to where I am.
As a team member of Aganoa...
I tried my best in every single challenge.
Then, when I went to Vavau...
I made my move.
Phoebe was gunning for me.
I managed to flip that around...
and then she went home.
Coming in...to this final merge...
my goal was
to ensure...that I could get out...
everyone from Vavau...
and everyone from Saanapu.
And that's what happened.
It was extraordinary to see how it unfolded.
At each stage...
I should've been going home.
My name was thrown around...
constantly. I have had
to fight my way through twenty
Tribal Councils.
In the end...
I was able to get through...two
whole tribes.
Who, in Survivor...
can say that?
I can.
Alright. Jury.
You've heard what Kristie and Lee have had to say.
And now it's your turn to ask a question.
And remember, you need to get enough information...
to make...that half-million dollar decision.
No pressure.
Alright. You got a minute to think about it...
and we'll get to it.
Alright. Jury.
You've heard what Kristie and Lee have had to say.
Now it's your turn to ask the question.
- El, you're up first.
- Oh, really.
- Yeah.
- Wow. First off. Off you go.
- Last out, first in.
- Hey, you guys.
- Congrats.
- Thank you.
Okay. Lee.
Yes.
I'm just wondering, yeah, if you do win...
What's one of the first selfless acts
that you'll, um, perform?
Um...
If I-If I do win, then...
first things first, is to look after...my mom and dad.
I've also got some, eh, philanthropic
work that I really wanna ramp up as well.
And not only that...my boys' education,
so, when it comes to...value served...
um...big ticket items, that's probably first in line...
to do with.
Alright, cool.
Kristie. Since day one...you never came up
to me with a move or I never saw any sort of game play.
How did you play this game...
and why should I vote for you?
I can definitely see how you feel like...
I didn't make any moves because,
yes, early on at Aganoa...everyone
just voted together and it was...easy targets.
Vavau...was...
the time that I played my strategy.
Basically the goal for Vavau was to...
eat away anyone that came into that tribe.
I managed to get through everyone in Vavau and
make it through to this final node.
But, when I was at Fia-Fia...the odds
were not in my favor at all.
There was nine of you...
who had...strong alliances, had been together for...
twenty-something days.
If I was you guys...
I would have just annihilated everybody...
and...then fought it out to the end.
Not to bag you at all...in the slightest.
But...me stepping back...
and watching that...is what I had to do to...stay in the game.
Cool. Alright. That's done.
Good luck, guys.
Flick.
Would you like to come down to the floor?
Ahh! Okay.
Kristie...
I think you upset a lot of people here...
on the jury. Including myself.
I feel like...there was
so many times...that you could have made big moves...
that would have been
in your best interest for the game.
But you didn't. Why do you think
you deserve to win...when...you...
didn't even really play the game?
It depends how you
define playing the game.
Playing the game can be done in so many different ways.
Yes, you can make big moves.
But sometimes it is about the smallest, subtle move.
I didn't have to
collaborate with you.
That's a move.
It's subtle...but it's a move.
It's not a show pony.
As Survivor fan, I can appreciate
every single one of you...
wanting to make big moves.
But...
you look at the jury and
the people who made big moves...
got voted out, straightaway afterwards.
So that's essentially...
not good game play for me.
Trust me...I wanted to be in it,
I wanted to be involved,
and I wanted to be a part of it all.
But, that's not how the cards were dealt...
when I got to that mess.
Thank you for your answer.
Thank you, Flick.
Brooke, would you like to come up?
Alright.
- Hey, guys.
- Hey, Brooke.
- Hey, congratulations to you both.
- Thank you.
- I'll start with you, Lee.
- Cool.
Is the jury correct
in assuming that there is a romantic
relationship between you and El?
Or...have you been kind of leading her on...
to help your strategy in the game?
Well, an answer to your question will be pretty short.
There is no romance...going on.
Yeah, yes, we spooned every night...
but, eh, it was a...a comfort
spoon more than anything. That's as far as it went.
I can assure you
that I have not lead El on at all...
with regards to our relationship.
What happens...outside of here, who knows.
But I do know this for sure,
we're gonna be very close friends.
At the very least.
Okay.
Kristie.
Your relationship with Lee has left me...
quite confused.
You've kind of...let...your dad
be Lee...take over all of your moves in this game
and that's how I've seen it.
Is just that...Lee's kind of, you know,
controlled your every move.
N...No.
Lee wasn't controlling me.
We were working
together and...I was...
very genuine with Lee...but...
part of my game play from the beginning...
was to let other people
think that they had control of me.
Everybody wants to feel secure in this game.
Everyone wants to feel like they're in control...
and know what's going on.
So...really...
I was kinda using Lee as well.
- Does that...
- Yeah, that does.
- clear it up?
- Well done, good answer.
- Thanks, guys.
- Thank  you.
Jennah Louise, you're up.
Hi, Kristie.
nice to meet you tonight.
- Wow.
- Uh...
Lee.
Ignorance and arrogance...
are two character traits...I do not favor.
Two character traits...
that you exude.
Arrogantly...you assumed...
that the people who wanted to win this game
were greedy...and money-hungry players.
You chastised me.
As humanitarian...
someone that voluntarily gives up their time
for some of the poorest people on earth...
that I was basically here...selfishly for the money.
Please explain to me...how someone
that exudes...ignorance and arrogance,
towards this game...does not
disrespect the "Sole Survivor" title...
and the game itself by being awarded it.
Discover what drives these 24 Aussies to win...
with castaway profiles at tenplay.com.au/survivor.
Lee.
Arrogantly...you chastised me...
a humanitarian...that I was basically here,
selfishly, for the money.
Please explain to me
how someone that exudes...
ignorance and arrogance towards this game...
does not disrespect the
"Sole Survivor" title...and the game itself by
being awarded it.
I do apologize for...eh,
bringing up money.
That was a-a-a moment's, eh, in the...
Tribal Council where,
you know, emotions got the better of me.
Eh, oh...Tribals Councils aren't my
forte, and, em...
it's-it's not me as a person, normally.
And...I just wanna apologize to you.
- Thanks, JL.
- Excellent. Thanks, guys, good luck.
Kylie.
- Wanna come down and join us?
- Love to.
- Congratulations, guys. Again, you two.
- Thanks, Kylie.
- Thank you, Kylie.
- You're sitting in a position that...
we, the jury, and so many other people...
can only dream of being. For me, personally,
I have such a deep respect of what...
the game of Survivor is...to outwit,
to outplay and to outlast...all others.
I also
especially have a deep respect...
for what the title...
that we'll be voting for, actually represents.
So I stand here and ask you to step up...
to be honest...
to own your game.
Thank you for your answers tonight,
because I came in here...
having an idea of who I think
deserves the title...but needing justification
to help my convictions.
So, please...you know, continue with that...
- completeness in your answers. And good luck.
- Thanks, Kyl.
Thanks.
Sam.
How are you, guys?
- Good. How are you, Sammy?
- Okay.
Lee.
I cannot...ignore the fact...that this perception...
does lay over you...for...
taking advantage of people that are vulnerable.
How did, or didn't you,
take advantage of Kristie...or manipulated her
to get to the final two?
I can see what you...wasn't...that's a good question
and...I wanted to make sure that she
was okay. Okay? Because we saw
what she went through in Aganoa...times.
And it wasn't pretty. Out of that, obviously,
it was-was chat about what's happening
in the game as well.
I understand that people might
see that in a different light
and people might see that as manipulation.
I didn't force her to do anything.
She probably played me as much as...
you people think that I played her.
Thanks.
Come on, Nick, come on up.
Hey, guys.
- Hey, Nick, how are you?
- Hi, Nick.
I've waited a long time to..
to say something.
- Let's get to it.
- Okay.
Okay, so Kristie...
What I know about you...
is...very little.
For a long time,
you haven't been able to articulate your
thoughts at all.
I sat there and I looked
at the way you would weave your arguments
and on the very rare occasion
when you actually said
anything at Tribal Council...
it often came out very stupid...
really felt almost as coherent as your gameplay.
It's interesting because tonight you have come out...
balls to the wall...and you have
literally been a different person.
You are not the Kristie that I have
been watching for the last few weeks.
- Lee.
- Nick.
Uh, I wanna talk to you tonight about your favorite topic.
Okay, so your favorite topic, in my opinion,
is morality. When you...we first started
playing together at Saanapu...
I...really enjoyed working with you.
- We got on like a house on fire.
- Yep.
And I don't know whether that was real or not...
but it certainly was genuine on my behalf.
We got to go off into the bush, we did manly things...
and that's not as weird in brokeback mountain as it seems.
And, eh, I really do enjoy our time together.
- Yep.
- I seriously do.
And while we were...chatting,
we would...you would often tell me about your
desire to play a moral game.
- And to play with honor and integrity.
- Yeah.
And I feel like you did snooker yourself.
Because, Lee...
time and time again...
You would retreat...to this place...
this almost magical land...
where...nobody voted for each other...
and the people who came here to
really play this game are forever shamed.
That place is the moral high ground.
And that is where you spent
fifty-five days of the game, in my opinion.
It was a place...where you would hear this morality
siren go off in your head like a tsunami warning...
and you would retreat to higher ground.
This pompous place of
valor and honor and integrity...
where Lieutenant Lee of the morality police...
would stand there and make judgment on
on other people for how they wanted to play the game.
I just don't know, in the spirit of
the way that you played to game...
if I can award the money...to a hypocrite
who doesn't uphold their moral values.
Overall...with regards to moral high ground...
that's what I wanted to do. I wanted to come in and
talk about...being the type of player that I wanted
to be in terms of, you know, being a trustworthy,
loyal and respectful.
- So we have to hold you...
- I know that.
- to that moral code.
- And...I...Exactly.
I have found out it is
nigh impossible to actually
execute that on Survivor.
And I didn't say that in my pitch,
that it's a good time to bring it up,
because it is...
a-a thing and what the hell have I got myself in for.
Why have I tried to...live this...
life in Survivor
which I can easily do in the outside world,
can easily do that...that's not a...problem.
Yet, that's what I was struggling with.
When I use those words: trust, loyalty and respect...
I was setting myself up for failure.
-  I-I honestly did.
- You seriously did.
- I did.
But I tried as hard as hard as I possibly could...
within the realm of Survivor to do that.
Because that's what I wanted to do, that I wanted to make
my boys proud...and that's all.
Good answer. Thank you. I appreciate that.
Well done, both of  you. Thanks, Jon.
Thanks, Nick.
Sue.
- Oh, good.
- Good one, Nick.
- Would you do us the honors?
- Hi, guys.
- Hi, Sue.
Kristie. Straight up.
- Hey, Sue.
- You did my head in.
You did a lot of flip-flopping.
I couldn't keep up with you.
Uh...one minute I thought...
yeah, we had something going and then,
the next, you've turned.
And I think you know that.
Of course. That's exactly right.
That's...ultimately...
what I had to do to, eh, stay in the game.
I'm extremely sorry that you ended up on the other...
end of it.
But...
every single tribal...
I've had hate coming towards me...
and I've had to move it.
And it's because of that strategy...
I went through the entire game...
through twenty Tribal Councils...
and knew who was going home...
every single time.
Well, you outsmarted me. Well done.
Matt. You're up.
- Kristie.
- Hey, Matty.
I-I feel in this game...
you know, there was this...lovely...caring...
friendly and supportive Kristie that I
genuinely really liked.
But, I also saw all this...manic and
panicked Kristie that...
was a little bit all over the place.
So here I am.
Looking...at possibly voting for you...to win...
- my childhood dream.
- Yeah.
So I need to know.
What Kristie...am I giving that dream to?
Cause I think that's important.
Okay. So...
I genuinely had two massive panic attacks...
panat the very beginning of this game.
And it did keep on reoccurring, to the point
that I didn't actually know that I
had anxiety...until...
getting into this game.
So...that's where you're seeing...the
disconnect...between...
these different Kristie's that you're saying.
But I managed to pick myself back up...and...
I think over the time
that I've been here...I have...
been able to display that...
you can beat all of the odds
in this game...no matter what you do.
The...whole essence of Survivor is
breaking through that adversity...
and if you can't do that...
where you gonna go?
Home.
Good answer. Well done.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, Matt.
Well, guys, you've heard...
Kristie and Lee, and you've had
your chance...to address them.
Now you should have all the information you need
make a decision about who you think
most deserves...the title of "Sole Survivor"
and the half-million dollars that goes with it.
Tonight...
Just to remember you...we are voting for a winner.
So...for the last time...
it is time to vote.
Well, guys, you've heard.
Kristie and Lee and you've had
your chance to address them.
Now you should have all the information you need
to make a decision about who you think
most deserves...the title of "Sole Survivor"
and the half-million dollars that goes with it.
Tonight...
jjust to remind you, we are voting for a winner.
So...for the last time...
it is time to vote.
Nick...this is it.
Oh, my hell.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Lee...we've been together many days.
Regardless, you played this game amazingly.
I love you, I respect you.
And you deserve to win.
I'd hoped...that someone could truly own the
title of "Sole Survivor".
You showed me that you earned it. Good luck.
I'll count the votes.
Okay.
Now, before I read the votes...there is one more thing.
It's a good thing.
In a moment, one of you will be named "Sole Survivor."
But a moment like that...
really...should be shared...
- Oh, my God.
- with people you care about the most.
Come on in, guys.
Lee.
Oh, my God. Are you kidding me?
I didn't even know anything.
I didn't know I would see you again.
- Good pleasing.
- I'm so proud.
We're proud of you, mate.
I missed you so much.
You're so beautiful.
No matter what the outcome...you're the winner, okay?
No matter what...no matter what the vote.
- You know that.
- I don't believe.
- So, Lee...
- Jon.
- I've met your sister.
- Yeah, Rachel.
- Can you introduce me to everyone else?
- Yeah, this is
- my mom, Beth.
- Hey, Beth.
- And this is, eh...Jake.
- Jake.
- and this is Sam.
- Sam.
So...two boys...
Missed 'em so much for the last fifty-five days.
- That you would believe,  so...to see their faces.
- I can't imagine.
They've grown so much.
Jake. What was it like seeing
your father for the first time in fifty-five days?
Um...proud.
What about the big grizzly beard that he's got?
- He looks like Obi Wan Kenobi.
- Obi Wan Kenobi?
I'll take that.
- Sam, what about you?
- Um...I'm really
proud of dad and...
I'm been very sad since he went.
Well, now you guys are back together.
So, Kristie. I've met your father.
Who's everyone else?
This is...my step-mom, Robin.
- This is my brother. And this is my mom.
- Hi. Hi, mom.
- Hi.
I'm so proud of her.
Been proud of her since the day she was born.
She knows that.
I love her so much.
Alright. Just a reminder. Tonight's vote
is for a winner.
And with nine jury members
it only takes...five votes.
Five votes. Five votes.
I'll read the votes.
First vote.
Kristie.
Lee.
That's one vote Kristie, one vote Lee.
Kristie.
That's two votes Kristie...one vote Lee.
Three votes Kristie...one vote Lee.
Kristie.
Four votes Kristie...one vote Lee.
Winner...of Australian Survivor...
Kristie.
Yeah, Kristie.
Kristie, congratulations.
Come over here and grab your check
for half-a-million dollars.
Kristie...
you are Australia's "Sole Survivor...2016".
Congratulations, babe.
You guys are just too much.
Amazing work. Amazing work, girl.
- Thank you so much.
- Amazing work.
Told you you couldn't do it, but you did.
Okay, you proved me wrong.
Good work, babe. Put it there.
I just won the title of "Sole Survivor".
Ahh.
And...half-a-mill. Ha-ha.
Survivor is the ultimate
game and the ultimate challenge.
You grow so much from going
through an experience like this and...
my life will never be the same.
Look at my baby girl.
I'm living proof
that if you want something, you can get it.
The biggest lesson that I've learned:
Be yourself, back yourself.
If you have a goal that you
deep down inside...know
- feels right...
- Who's a girl?
it is right.
I don't know how...you've done this.
But it's imspiring.
It's incredible...
and this is proof...that anything
is possible.
You deserve to be the "Sole Survivor".
Well deserved. Good on you.
But you're still a naughty little girl.
I never thought I'd be writing your name down
as part of the game or that you'd
even make it this far, but...
good on you and you've only entered today.
Well done, too.
This game is definitely of the sixth sense of Heila.
You beat me alright.
You genuinely got me at...the hardest game...
on earth. I'm so proud of you. Well done.
You lived your dream.
I'd hoped that someone could truly
own the title of "Sole Survivor".
You showed me that you earned it.
Ohhh.
Wow. I can't believe that I just did this.
Nick out.